Hey everyone, welcome back and let's write some more neat code today. So today let's
solve a pretty easy and popular question invert binary search tree. So all they tell us to
do is invert a binary tree. And what exactly does that mean? So let's say that this is
our initial tree. To invert it is basically what you can tell in the output, right? So
the root stayed the same, but you can see it's two children which were left child to
left or right child seven were swapped, right? So seven is now on the other side. Two has
been moved, right? So basically we took these and then we swapped them. And when they say
invert the binary tree, it's a recursive definition. So take a look at this sub tree, right? You
can see since we moved it to this side, that's where it is, right? But notice how even these
sub trees are different now, right? One was initially on the left and three was initially
on the right, but now three is on the left and one is on the right. The exact same thing
happened with this tree, right? It was moved over here to the left side, but then its children
were also swapped, right? So nine was moved to the left, six to the right. So when they
say invert the binary tree, what we're saying is visit every single node in the tree, right?
And every time we visit a node, take a look at its two children and swap the positions
of the children, right? So in other words, if we're given a tree, look at the root node
and take its children and then swap the positions and then recursively run invert tree on the
left sub tree and run invert on the right sub tree. So it's a recursive definition.
So we can solve this problem with recursion. We can do a depth first search, whether it's
preorder or post order, it doesn't actually matter. A depth first search will allow us
to solve this problem recursively. So this problem would probably be a lot more annoying
if it were iterative, but luckily we can do it recursively. So we can first check the
base case. So if the root is null, then we can return null. We don't have to continue.
Otherwise what we're going to do is swap the children. So we're going to save the left
value root left in a temporary variable. Then we're going to replace the root left value
with root right. And then we're going to replace the root right value with the left value,
which we know is now stored in temp. So after we swap the nodes, all we have to do is now
recursively invert the sub trees so we can invert the left sub tree and then we can invert
the right sub tree. So by doing self dot invert tree, what we're doing is making a recursive
call to the function we're inside. And once we have swapped the roots, children, once
we have inverted the left sub tree and inverted the right sub tree, we know we're finished.
So then we can return the root. So there it is. This problem is relatively short code.
It's a very good problem to kind of understand the basics of depth first search and tree
problems in general. And it's actually a pretty popular problem. And if you weren't able to
solve this on your first try, don't feel too bad. Take a look at this trivia. There was
a very good engineer who actually failed this problem in their Google interview, but his
career still turned out pretty fine. So I hope this was helpful. If it was, please like
and subscribe. It supports the channel a lot and I'll hopefully see you pretty soon.